# Sergey Tulyakov

University of Trento sergey.tulyakov@unitn.it http://www.stulyakov.com/ https://github.com/sergeytulyakov

## Summary

Specializes in 2D and 3D computer vision, machine learning, generative and discriminative modeling, digital signal processing. Has extensive background in software engineering.

Current research interests: Discriminative and generative modeling, image and video generation, face alignment, tracking, head pose estimation in 2D and 3D, higher-level activity recognition such as facial expressions, heart rate recognition from video, with particular emphasis on facial analysis in difficult realistic scenarios.

Technical skills: C++, Python, C#, Qt, Boost, CMake, Shell, Unix, Windows, macOS Scientific computing: Eigen, dlib, OpenCV, PointCloudLibrary(PCL), scientific python stack, Theano, Chainer, Matlab

#### Education

Oct 2012 –	University of Trento (Trento, Italy)
Apr 2017	PhD in Computer Science.
	Thesis: A Computer Vision Perspective on Face Analysis: Registration, Tracking,
	Synthesis
Nov 2014 -	Carnegie Mellon University (Pittsburgh, USA)
Feb 2015	Research intern at Robotics Institute
Sept 2009 –	Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics (Minsk, Belarus)
July 2010	Master in Computer Science. Final grade: 9 out of 10
v	
Sept 2004 –	Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics (Minsk, Belarus)
July 2009	Bachelor in Computer Science. Diploma with distinction. GPA 8.9. Final grade:
	10 out of 10

# Scientific projects

- The **ACANTO** project aims at increasing the number of older adults who engage in a regular and sustained physical activity. Developed a real-time method for instantaneous heart rate recognition from face videos.
- The **DALi Devices for Assisted Living** project aimed at extending autonomous live of elderly people beyond home. Developed a real-time system for head pose analysis, tracking and facial expression recognition under a wide range of head poses.
- The purpose of the **PerTe Persuasive Technology** project was to aid groups of people in a brainstorming environment. Worked on user monitoring part: track faces, measure attention given/received and analyze speech activity of the subjects.

# Personal projects

- Facify is a face tracking and 3D face reconstruction technology, enabling real-time face analysis on low-power mobile devices. The technology features a tiny hard drive footprint (20mb) and impressive tracking speed (200 frames per second on iPhone 6)
- FaceCept Face perCept is a technology that allows real-time analysis of people's faces. Key features: gender, age, facial expression, new/returning, attention time recognition. The technology is cross-platform: it runs even in a browser.
- FaceCept3D is a flexible open-source technology for 3D face analysis and recognition, available on GitHub. Key features: head pose, facial expression and action units recognition in real time. FaceCept3D handles head pose ranges much wider than other systems.

# Work experience

01/2017 - 04/2017 Research intern at NVIDIA (Santa Clara, CA, US)

Worked on motion-content decomposed video generation using Generative Adversarial

Networks with Ming-Yu Liu and Jan Kautz.

08/2016 - 11/2016 Research intern at Microsoft Research (Cambridge, UK)

Together with Sebastian Nowozin and Andrew Fitzgibbon worked on building efficient hybrids of deep generative and discriminative models, that benefit from using unlabeled

data.

07/2010 - 09/2012 Senior software engineer, project lead at HiQo Solutions, Inc (Minsk, Belarus)

06/2006 – 06/2010 Software engineer at Todes, Ltd. (Minsk, Belarus)

### Professional activities

Events: Chair of the first Workshop on 3D Face Alignment in the Wild (3DFAW) & Challenge

organized in conjunction with ECCV 2016.

**Reviewer:** International Conference on Computer Vision 2017

Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2017

International Conference on Face and Gesture Recognition 2017

European Conference on Computer Vision 2016 International Conference on Pattern Recognition 2016

IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing

IEEE Transactions on Multimedia Elsevier Image and Vision Computing

# Publications and patents

[1] S. Tulyakov, M.-Y. Liu, X. Yang, and J. Kautz. *MoCoGAN: Decomposing Motion and Content for Video Generation*. Submitted to International Conference on Computer Vision, 2017.

- [2] S. Tulyakov, A. Fitzgibbon, and S. Nowozin *Hybrid-VAE: Improving Deep Generative Models using Partial Observations*. Submitted to International Conference on Computer Vision, 2017.
- [3] László A. Jeni, Sergey Tulyakov, Lijun Yin, Nicu Sebe, and Jeffrey F. Cohn *The First 3D Face Alignment in the Wild (3DFAW) Challenge*. European Conference on Computer Vision, 2016.
- [4] [Oral] W. Wang, S. Tulyakov, N. Sebe. Recurrent Convolutional Face Alignment. Asian Conference on Computer Vision, 2016.
- [5] S. Tulyakov, L. A. Jeni, N. Sebe, and J. Cohn. *Viewpoint-consistent 3D Face Alignment*. Submitted to Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence.
- [6] [Oral] S. Tulyakov, X. Alameda-Pineda, E. Ricci, L. Yin, N. Sebe, and J. Cohn. Self-Adaptive Matrix Completion for Heart Rate Estimation from Face Videos under Realistic Conditions. Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2016.
- [7] S. Tulyakov and N. Sebe. Regressing a 3D Face Shape from a Single Image. In International Conference on Computer Vision, 2015.
- [8] S. Tulyakov, R. L. Vieriu, E. Sangineto and N. Sebe. FaceCept3D: Real Time 3D Face Tracking and Analysis. In International Conference on Computer Vision Workshops, 2015.
- [9] R. L. Vieriu, S. Tulyakov, E. Sangineto, S. Semeniuta, and N. Sebe. Facial Expression Recognition under a Wide Range of Head Poses. In Face and Gesture Recognition, 2015.
- [10] S. Tulyakov, R. L. Vieriu, S. Semeniuta, and N. Sebe. *Robust Real-Time Extreme Head Pose Estimation*. In International Conference on Pattern Recognition, 2014.
- [11] [Patent] S. Tulyakov, M-Y. Liu, X. Yang, and J. Kautz. Method for content and motion controlled action video generation. Patent Application No: 62/354,475.
- [12] [Patent] S. Tulyakov, X. Alameda-Pineda, E. Ricci, L. Yin, N. Sebe, and J. Cohn. Self-Adaptive Matrix Completion for Heart Rate Estimation from Face Videos under Realistic Conditions. Patent Application No: 62/480,094.